ana so it's your first match are you
ready i am ready
don't be nervous okay it's gonna be okay
who did you uh who's coming
christine there's somebody from your
clinic right
okay good do you know what her rating is
i have no idea like has she been playing
tennis for a while
i mean we rallied well no but has she
been playing for a while
that i don't know i think she's she's an
experienced player
she's a little more experienced than me
yeah but you guys
can match up well right i think she
started when she was a kid
oh she did i think so anna this is going
to be tough match
okay it doesn't matter it doesn't matter
guys before you play any match you have
to decide who's going to surf first and
you can here on the bottom of your
racket you have um
usually either a logo or like a letter
like will
your wilson for example has mr w so you
can spin it in the air you ask the other
person if they want a
m or a w
so then you spin it down the ground like
this and let's see where it ends up
let's let the racket go let it fall on
the ground like spin it
okay all right so what did you say again
you said w so it's uh m okay so you get
to choose and here are your choices
you can pick serve first or receive
first or you can pick which side you
want to be on
in today's sk in today's case we won't
switch sides
make a little bit easier on you guys um
but you want to serve first
yeah alright great all right guys good
luck thank you
all right now look um nothing special
you just
play without much thought you just
the simple tactics are you want to try
not to miss and
get a nice big general target you can go
down the middle of the court and keep
the ball going especially early on so
you can loosen up a little bit
are you feeling nervous at all no okay
good yeah all right
all right good it's just a game exactly
[Applause]
okay when you get pushed back like that
are you scared to hit the camera you're
actually really far away don't worry
about the camera in my mind
no no just gotta ignore that you're
really far away you got plenty of space
here
when you get pushed back a little bit
get some height on the ball put it a
little bit higher you need two balls
you need two balls you always need two
balls if in case you miss your first
serve
you have a second ball handy you don't
have to go pick it up
yeah move that ball real quick when the
ball gets into the net and it's in the
cord
get it out of the way move that other
one too just in case
anna what a rally this is crazy
really good just keep going like that
that was amazing
no no you're probably a little bit tight
but it's okay you're doing really well
one thing that will keep your feet
moving a little more
when you're not hitting and come back to
the middle here's another ball always
take two balls
fifteen all i'm gonna help you to score
and make sure when the ball is out you
call it okay so she knows that
it's out yeah but you say it right away
that was kind of obvious but if it's
closer you need to let her know
you know yeah yeah you have to stay out
you can scream you can say it quietly
whatever as soon as
as long as she hurts hears it you know
rihanna always take two balls though
that was out yeah good call so now we
got 40 15 you have game points
don't flick the hand keep the hand open
as you toss like this
all right double fault it's okay shake
it off one thing i want to tell you
about keep
continuing to toss the ball up like many
times in a row
it gets really frustrating not only for
yourself but also for the opponent yeah
you know so i would say if you do it
once it's okay but on the second time
just hit it even though it might be a
bad toss
because you can get in your head the
more you keep the more you keep
repeating and trying to fix your
thoughts
the more wrong it goes so dawn continues
to keep throwing
it until you get it right there's a time
limit in tennis by the way
yeah yeah you don't have all you don't
you don't have all day between points
all right here we go come on 40 30.
okay you know what that wasn't really a
bad technical
shot there was a good backhand but the
location was bad did you aim there
to the line yeah it's too risky
so you want to aim in a more central
location that's what caused you to miss
but it's okay you're still in this game
as deuce now okay
deuce deuces 40 all right 40 off
good
and what i notice is when you get a
short ball you try always hit it back
short
yes you hit it don't do that because
you end up pushing the ball guiding it
steering it even when you're shorter
still finish your forehand
don't go too hard but still finish it
always finish it okay so it's add out
you keep going okay she has a break
point now so you got to get this one
okay
okay you we're up 40 15 you end up
losing the game no big deal
okay are you how are you feeling
mentally are you still a little bit i'm
okay no it's just like
this surf actually i did much better
okay on other days i don't know
it's all right like shaking but that's
what i mean so you're probably a little
bit anxious
a little bit nervous it's going to go
away just keep going keep that ball in
play come on
the middle middle
see anna what a rally
you're a little tactician out there are
you doing this stuff on purpose or it's
all accidents
okay all right all right you doing good
luck you're doing good just keep going
love 30 now try to get this game
all right
well if you hit it that bad like that
was kind of like a shank you can say to
her sorry
that's like the tennis etiquette if you
hit a really lucky shot you can just
raise your hand and say sorry oh
it's not a lucky shot it's like
all right love 40. come on get this
break back
middle middle
middle anna
you're being moved like a yo-yo up and
down all right
listen you when you're up there close
you can also volley
you see you come to the net and you keep
backing up remember alex we did him
you take the ball in the air i'm i'm
never sure when to get
just stay there you can if you're very
close to the net you stay there
you don't have time to back up yeah 15
40. come on get this game right here
[Applause]
please
all right listen couple of things not a
bad rally what you should never do is
talk in the
inside the rally first of all it's not
allowed anyway tennis rules yeah you're
not
uh supposed to say anything during a
rally it's called hindrance
but also it takes your concentration
away you notice how you you started
talking and you missed the next backhand
middle
corner all right all right anna you're
on the board
excellent job it's one one that you're
serving okay
and try to get ahead in the in the game
now when it comes to the serve
you toss you were tossing it way too
much you were losing confidence from
there so i want you to
make less attempts on the toss and just
hit them even though it's a bad
comment right here
anna nice you see you put a little bit
of height on that forehand
and she had a hard time the toast was
successful so okay here we go
don't don't forget to call it though you
say out
she saw it i've done i know it's obvious
there i just want to get used to calling
the balls
maybe the best four hands you hit all
day you see you're getting more
confidence now you notice it
getting confidence you got two balls all
right here we go
30 love
finish
okay interesting choice that you did
like an open stance backhand but you
notice you're not really finishing your
backhands you're stopping halfway
make sure you finish it all the way have
trust in your back and it's a good shot
yeah you're stopping it halfway i don't
know if you can feel that or not
no but just make sure you finish all the
way okay okay yeah here we go
okay it's double fault right all right
30 all
it's no big deal shake it off double
faults are part of the game
and you're going to get this one right
here 30 very important point because
either it's game point for you
or breakpoint for her oh you already got
one let's get that first serve in
good
well i didn't think you hit it like by
accident you hit a great shot you don't
have to say sorry
you said the office you say come on come
on yeah you can do that that was
your first winner of the match winner
means when you hit a ball and she can't
get it back
so that was you i love christine i just
like that well you don't have to feel
bad
it's a friendly match you've been very
fair so far yeah but there was a
great back and keep going like that 40
30. come on
okay you were too open on that back and
you ran right into it remember you got
to turn a little more on the back and
when you're too open it's going to go
crooked it's going to go sideways a lot
all right no big deal
anna again your high forehand is giving
her a lot of trouble you notice that
when you put the ball a little bit
higher with more spin she has a lot
she's a hard time
call it out all right now you win that
game that was a huge game to win because
now you're up to one so let's
keep now just keep going like this now
you want to go up 3-1
okay so you win the next game how many
games did we play so far
um we played so far at three games and
you're up
you're up two one you go up to six all
right so obviously if you you just
continue
you know increasing your lead it's going
to be easier to win the set if it stays
close
mentally you're going to feel like more
anxious is going to be more tight
because the outcome is more uncertain so
generally what happens as you build the
lead her confidence goes down
yours goes up
see i heard you say something during
that backhand you see how you didn't
finish it
just kind of bunted it there it worked
you got a little lucky
but you didn't finish that backhand yeah
you bunted it make sure you finish all
the way okay
you trust it go right here low 15.
middle
on the middle
very nice shot very good
uh you're camping out over here too much
you know you're stuck in bad situations
you gave her a really weak paw that she
took advantage of
so keep keeping aggressive you're
playing well now you can go a little bit
stronger on your shots
okay all right over there fifteen all
out very good call anna and yes it was
out 15 30. great rally
middle
okay anna you see that one forehead it
looked like it was going to go out
and then it came in it was because you
put a little bit of spin on there
very nice 1540 now you got break point
okay
you try to get this game slide over to
that side
no problem it's a tough shot but also
you're hitting a backhand from the
forehand side
what do you prefer right now which shot
you could have just moved this way
so what do you what do you prefer to hit
right now 400 what do you trust more
it's 50 50. perhaps yeah okay well in
that case you didn't didn't do
too bad of a decision to try to hit a up
from there generally speaking everything
on this side would be a forehand but you
were coming from this corner so a lot of
times you don't get back to the middle
enough you're kind of camping out on the
sides too much all right so get back to
the middle every time okay
30 40. you got one breakpoint left get
it right here come on
all right too weak it's okay
it's too weak maybe a little bit of
tension in your arm the arm was heavy
you know you couldn't get any power
no biggie we keep going deuce no no no
it's deuce
so you just had break points which you
didn't convert
and now it's deuce now it's like 4 40
all and now it's deuce you need two in a
row to win
so you're very still very close to um
win this game what happens often is when
you have these opportunities to win the
game and you don't
a lot of players get very disappointed
and then they start doing very badly
oh yeah so you just forget about it just
do you know if you didn't
oh you don't even remember that you just
had two break points
i'm just playing no you've got to keep
your mind on the score though because
the score is
very very important how are you going to
play this game but
this way if you if you no mental spaces
i understand but that you can't play
tennis like that first of all if i'm not
here you're gonna have to keep score
you have to think about the score every
single point
okay maybe that's a bad thing next time
i'll i'll just put the camera up and
i'll leave
okay and then i'll check the results
later over there deuce
anna that's when you say sorry to
christine you can say sorry
i understand it was a completely lucky
shot right so you're just tennis
etiquette says you just put your hand up
and say sorry
okay you go over there add out now you
got break point anna
slide over that way
again too weak remember when you get
pushed further back
which you are now you put more height or
the ball's gonna die especially if
you're tight and you have a heavy arm
all right deuce go back over here
okay you overcooked it a little bit you
put too much steam on that forehand
all right here christine now she has
game point let's add in
you come back over here on this side ana
over here
okay see how you're not finishing the
back end though you're being too careful
you're being too careful all right no
biggies to all
nothing happened you had a couple of
opportunities that didn't convert you
just tension going
but you see what i mean there's tension
when it's close score yeah that's what i
was saying before you want to build the
lead
but no problem we keep going it's too
all you get this next game right here
come on
i think we've got christine it's it's uh
8 13. let's just go up to
four because you got to leave at 8 30
right yeah so we do first one up to four
it's two all
okay if it's three all we play sudden
death
okay now look she's
kind of getting in the groove now you
got to start thinking about maybe
opening the cord up a little more
putting the ball in the corners a little
bit maybe
yeah start thinking about it because
going through the middle is not working
that great
because she's not missing anymore so try
to open up the cord a little bit
you were blocking my view but i'm pretty
sure it was in was it
it was kind of like yeah it was good
right because i couldn't really see it
but i think i was in
um so what happens actually because you
called it out and was then you lose the
point
that's the rules huh yeah that's the
rule so you called it
out but it was actually in you
unfortunately lose that point yeah yeah
so it's a lot 30. i felt like it was
like yeah it's okay it can happen
sometime
at all yeah even if it touches
see even a millimeter on the line is
still in christina's right about that so
it's
just love 30 your point i don't think
we've ever talked about it
not in that least detail
good
it's okay you caught the frame a little
bit it's all right
i love 40. all right now you now you're
in a big
you're in biggest trouble in your serve
but no biggie you want to claw back into
this game by getting this point right
here okay
all right anna again a little bit too
weak when you get pushed back you need a
little more strength because those balls
are dying on you
all right listen you got broken no big
deal there's two three
since we're only going up to force you
only need one more game to win the whole
thing so you got to get this one right
here okay
come on okay this is no biggie you just
got to get this game where it's over
all right here we go yeah to wipe them
off with a towel i recommend even get a
like a wristband you know oh yeah that's
what they're for
yeah wristband will stop sweat from
rolling onto your hands
good
okay well that was what was good about
that foreign you put it a little bit
away from her you put it to the side a
little bit
so you can try doing that now in this
game you put the ball a little bit away
from the middle
anna why was the sneaky shot there
was that actually it was normal was that
on purpose no
i mean not just how it was very calm but
you didn't finish finish that backhand
you got actually lucky there was a lucky
shot finish your back and
yeah finish it both finish them both
meaning they go all the way
all the way you're just kind of tapping
and bunting the ball which is normal
because you want to get the ball in very
badly it's very common
all right here we go love 30.
good
morning
okay anna
good call
oh yes it was it was out that's it
so it's now it's three all because you
have to go
we'll play we're going up to four let's
play deciding game winner takes all
right and anna's serving see when you're
not around i have christine
she knows she knows how to keep score
really well yeah
yeah you should definitely play with her
more this would be great great practice
for you
but uh nevertheless now it's it's time
to shine because this is sudden death
winner takes all anna oh stop all right
here we go i'm just hyping you up a
little bit okay come on
well obviously it's important game three
all right the winner takes takes the
whole thing
so if you feel a little bit tense move
your feet more
okay also breathe don't forget to
breathe alright here we go you got this
anna
anna maybe the best rally of the match
great job guys that was a really nice
rally it was really good
really long yeah very good good little
backhand there see that was an exception
where you
don't really have to finish the ball was
very close to the net it was very low
you couldn't have finished there you
were fine doing the little buns all
right 15 left come on keep going
okay you know what a lot you scare the
camera but
you're so far away you don't have to
worry if you get close i'm going to tell
you
so just get that out of your head
because you have plenty of space but i
love the way you played this rally that
was a really good point
so christine hit a very deep ball and
you you got a hard shot there but
there was some really good forehands
there keep going like that okay 15
all
it was a little bit long it's okay anna
no shake it off it's all right 15 30.
okay yeah again your head hit upside
down
you hit a fantastic forehand cross score
you had the whole court open you decided
to do something different
simply go back the other way but don't
worry about it it's okay
now if you realize 1540 is match point
her
all right so you got to get this point
otherwise it's going to be over come on
get this point right here it's a little
bit of pressure but you can do it come
on
all right one match point saved very
good job anna
anna two match points saved but now keep
going get this point right here
and you got yourself a match point okay
come on no pressure
all right tell us all about pressure
here we go
anna you overcooked it but good try it's
okay you overcooked it just a little bit
all right no problem match point number
three let's get it back okay
keep fighting
all right no problem again very common
here do a racket tap with me you did
fantastic job on it you did
really really well the stuff that was
happening uh we'll talk about it later
but first you got to go shake hands with
christine or do a racket tap
great match christine good playing nice
work anna
don't be sad okay it's okay
it's okay there's tennis you win or lose
you were so close
i'm not a teenager i can hold my ground
but you see now what i was telling you
when we were preparing for the match how
you cannot recreate the emotions that
you're feeling during a real match
in practice why because it depends on
the score line first of all you're
nervous in general to compete a little
bit but then when the match starts
there's going to be certain things
happening in the match certain score
lines that are gonna make you feel
nervous and anxious so that's what makes
tennis so challenging
but also what makes it so fun because
now don't you want to play again
oh i can't wait and give yourself
another chance yeah
with christine but a couple of things i
want to tell you as far as your
technique
and number one the serve needs a lot of
work it's okay i didn't really say
anything because
when you play a match you can't really
do technique so i didn't say anything
technical other than like try to finish
your strokes okay
which is also a mental thing because
when you're tight you don't finish
you're kind of bunt
so finishing that's okay thing to try to
do
uh during the course of a match when it
comes to the serve it's so complex we're
going to have to work on it and
really spend a lot of time because your
your service still pretty much at a
beginner level
i'm really happy about your forehand
though do you see how well your forehand
was working
let's get in there yeah still like the
consistency is iffy
yeah but i i love the way you're hitting
your forehand
backhand i was surprised that you
weren't finishing it often you would
just go halfway you were bunting it
placement of the ball we got to work on
two i think as the match progressed when
you got a little bit deeper into the set
you started opening the cord up a little
more in the beginning you were hitting
everything uh
through the middle which i like but
eventually christine got used to that
and then she stopped missing so much
then it's time to start opening the cord
and make life a little bit more
difficult for her so placement of the
ball is another thing
that you got to work on and court
positioning you're often in no man's
land
you know stuck in the middle of the
court so we got to work on it too but i
have to say for your first match ever
you did fantastically well you did a
really good job
i know it's really humid so this hands
were like super sweaty
oh your hands were sweating you said
about the wristband something during the
game i wasn't sure
well it's just one of those this uh
summertime in florida so so you just
like
rub your hand on the wristband i was
always curious wow
here's a couple of things you can do
with the wristband first of all it does
block some of the sweat from
pouring onto your hand which will make
it which will make the
which will make the grip wet and also
you can wipe yourself off a little bit
with the wristband as well
i thought it was styling thing i'm like
i have to get them too it's a little bit
of style too
but they do have a you know practical
purpose
for sure and always like when it's hot
like this you want to take a towel with
you to the back fence like you did
and towel off dry your grip especially
you know but um yeah there was a really
good
first match i'm very positively
surprised actually
because first time playing a match is
always very difficult it's nerve-racking
you didn't double fault that many times
and even though the server wasn't
technically
technically correct you still was able
to get it in most of the time
and you rallied you had a lot of long
rallies yes which is fabulous
so the more matches you play the more
you lose some of these nerves that you
have now
and you're going to start playing more
freely and you're going to start playing
your practice game
in a match situation all right anna good
work
all right very nice no thank you that
was good thank you i'm sorry again for
yesterday
i apologize i hope you're not mad at me
is it on the camera too
no i'm not going to say that i'm not
going to put on a camera